scifinow.co.uk 2019-06-21

# Privacy Policy | Kelsey Media

Data Protection is an integral part of the Company’s business practices and Kelsey Publishing Limited and Kelsey Media Ltd (‘Kelsey’ or ‘we’) is committed to protecting your personal information, whether you are a business contact; a customer or prospect interested in our services; an employee or freelancer or a supplier of Kelsey.

This privacy policy explains how Kelsey looks after your personal data in accordance with General Data Protection Regulations (GDPR) and also explains your rights.

**1.0 BUSINESS CONTACT INFORMATION**

1.1 We may hold business contact data if you are a decision maker in an organisation that is someone who buys media opportunities for your company, so that we are able to speak to you about Kelsey and its offerings.   This data would have been supplied directly to us by you or via one of our sales houses and is held on a central database to enable us to manage and monitor contact preferences. Your data can only be used where the potential opportunity with Kelsey Media might be relevant to you in your professional capacity.

1.2 The sales houses, include Talk Media Sales, Tandem Media, TigerBee Media, Hill View Media Ltd and David Lane.

1.3 The personal data we hold centrally is your name, job title, company and contact details, including your preferred email address and telephone number where supplied.

1.4 We want to respect your wishes about how and if you are contacted.  You will always receive an email when your details are added to our database so that we can confirm and collect your consent to be contacted in the future.

1.5 The legal basis for processing your data is ‘legitimate interest’ because Kelsey benefits from advertising booked across the range of its brands.

1.6 We do not use your personal data for any automated decision making or profiling.

1.7 Your rights concerning your personal data are:

  * You can ask to see the personal data we hold about you and we will show you, free of charge
  * We will update the personal data to correct errors when you tell us about them
  * We will supply you with an electronic copy of the personal data we hold about you if you ask us to
  * We will stop processing your personal data if you tell us to
  * We will delete your personal data if you ask us to. The law says we must not contact you again if you ask us not to.  For this reason, we may need to keep the paper trail confirming deletion to make sure this happens

1.8 If you wish to contact us, please refer to Section 7 of this policy.

**2.0 CUSTOMERS / PROSPECTS**

2.1 When you sign up to our services, such as our website forums, mobile applications, regular newsletters, enter competitions, buy a magazine, buy event tickets, order products or take up a reader offer, we may ask for personal information about you, and hold this information to enable us to contact you.

2.2 The personal information we hold could include your name, e-mail address, postal address, telephone or mobile number, date of birth and any specific requests, events, titles etc that you may have purchased or enquired about.   Different services may ask for different types of information.

2.3 If you are aged 16 or under, you must get your parent/guardian’s permission before you provide us with your personal information.  Unless you have this consent, you are not allowed to give us your information.

2.4 We do not store credit card details.

2.5 Relevant personal data will be shared with contracted 3rd party companies engaged to fulfil our subscription obligations and/or deliver products and services, including Events.

2.6 Relevant personal data will be shared with credit reference agencies if Kelsey agrees to extend credit to a buyer or exhibitor.

2.7 We will not share any of your personal details with any 3rd party companies for marketing purposes without collecting your explicit consent.   However, on occasion with relation to subscription updates and renewals, we do use a company called PNL to assist our team with the renewals process.

2.8 In relation to Audit Bureau of Circulation Ltd (ABC), we are obliged to supply random subscription information to ensure that our magazine sales are legitimised.   Here is the link to ABC for information on their privacy notice – https://www.abc.org.uk/privacy-policy

2.9 It is possible we might have to disclose this information for legal purposes.

2.10 The legal basis for processing your data is ‘legitimate interest’.  Kelsey benefit from subscriptions, advertising, events tickets and sales of products and would like you to order again.

2.11 We do not use your personal data for any automated decision making or profiling.  This website may contain adverts. These will typically be served through our advertising partners who may have detailed privacy policies relating directly to the adverts they serve.  Clicking on any such adverts will send you to the advertiser’s website through a referral program which may use cookies and will track the number of referrals sent from this website.

This may include the use of cookies which may in turn be saved on your computer’s hard drive. Users should therefore note they click on sponsored external links at their own risk and this website and its owners cannot be held liable for any damages or implications caused by visiting any external links mentioned.

A Cookie is a small text file that stores a small amount of data about your website visit.  We may use Cookies to:

  * help you to navigate the site and to use its services and features
  * collect information about your choices and preferences
  * enable you to share pages and content on social media
  * collect analytics to inform us about use of the site and enable us to improve it.Analytics Cookies allow us to see the overview patterns of usage on the site; we do not examine this information for individually identifiable information.
  * To display targeted promotions or advertisements based upon your interests on the site or to manage our advertising. These Cookies collect information about your activities on this website and others to provide you with targeted advertising.

You can choose whether to accept Cookies by changing the settings on your browser.

2.12 We will continue contacting you after you have stopped being an active customer for a period of two years.  After this point we will either delete your data or keep it because you have asked us to.

2.13 Your rights concerning your personal data are:

  * You can ask to see the personal data we hold about you and we will show you, free of charge
  * We will update the personal data to correct errors when you tell us about them
  * We will supply you with an electronic copy of the personal data we hold about you if you ask us to
  * We will stop processing your personal data if you tell us to
  * We will delete your personal data if you ask us to. The law says we must not contact you again if you ask us not to.  For this reason, we may need to keep the paper trail confirming deletion to make sure this happens

2.14 If you wish to contact us, please refer to Section 7 of this policy.

** ** **3.0 EMPLOYEES**

3.1 As an employer, Kelsey needs to keep and process information about employees for management and administrative use only.    Kelsey will securely store it and use it to enable us to run the business and manage our relationship with you effectively, lawfully and appropriately.    This will commence from the beginning of the recruitment process, throughout your employment with us and after you have left our employment.

3.2 The personal information we hold will enable us to employ, pay and manage your work.   The sort of information we hold on you includes your name, address and contact details, date of birth, next of kin, employment, contract and benefit details and history, payroll details, bank details, identification details (to confirm right to work in the UK), holiday and absence information.

3.3 We only disclose information about you to third parties if we are legally obliged to do so or where we need to comply with our contractual duties to you.  For example, we will need to pass on specific information to our external payroll provider; pension, critical health and death in service scheme provider; and health care and childcare vouchers scheme facilitator.

3.4 Further details can be found in Kelsey’s Company Handbook.

3.5 Your rights concerning your personal data are:

  * You can ask to see the personal data we hold about you and we will show you, free of charge
  * We will update the personal data to correct errors when you tell us about them
  * We will supply you with an electronic copy of the personal data we hold about you if you ask us to
  * We will stop processing your personal data if you tell us to
  * We will delete your personal data if you ask us to. The law says we must not contact you again if you ask us not to.  For this reason, we may need to keep the paper trail confirming deletion to make sure this happens

3.6 If you wish to contact us, please refer to Section 7 of this policy.

** ** **4.0 FREELANCERS & CONTRIBUTORS**

4.1 As a publisher, freelancers and contributors are engaged to provide various outsourced services across all our brands and events, and as such Kelsey needs to keep and process information about you for management and administrative use only.   Kelsey will securely store it and use it to enable us to run the business and manage our relationship with you effectively, lawfully and appropriately.    This will commence from the beginning of the freelance agreement, throughout the duration of the freelance agreement and after the agreement has ended.

4.2 This will include using information to comply with the freelance agreement, comply with any legal requirements, pursue the legitimate interests of the company and protect our legal position in the event of proceedings.

4.3 All of the information we hold will have been provided by you.  The sort of information we hold on you includes your name, address and contact details, freelance agreement details and bank details.

4.4 The legal basis for processing your data is ‘contract’ whilst you are engaged as a freelancer/contributor and sometimes ‘legal requirement’ in case of certain records.

4.5 We do not use your personal data for any automated decision making or profiling.

4.6 Your rights concerning your personal data are:

  * You can ask to see the personal data we hold about you and we will show you, free of charge
  * We will update the personal data to correct errors when you tell us about them
  * We will supply you with an electronic copy of the personal data we hold about you if you ask us to
  * We will stop processing your personal data if you tell us to
  * We will delete your personal data if you ask us to. The law says we must not contact you again if you ask us not to.  For this reason, we may need to keep the paper trail confirming deletion to make sure this happens

4.7 If you wish to contact us, please refer to Section 7 of this policy.

**5.0 JOB APPLICANTS**

5.1 We hold information about job applicants to enable us to contact you.

5.2 The personal information we hold will have been provided by you and will be your name, address, contact information, current and previous job details.

5.3 The information is only disclosed to those key staff involved in the recruitment process for the job you have applied for.

5.4 We will retain information on all applicants for a maximum period of 6 months, in line with recommended minimum retention periods; unless you have specifically requested we hold your details for future job opportunities.

5.5 Any data received through pre-employment checks that results in a withdrawal of job offer will be securely destroyed.

5.6 We do not use your personal data for any automated decision making or profiling.

5.7 Your rights concerning your personal data are:

  * You can ask to see the personal data we hold about you and we will show you, free of charge
  * We will update the personal data to correct errors when you tell us about them
  * We will supply you with an electronic copy of the personal data we hold about you if you ask us to
  * We will stop processing your personal data if you tell us to
  * We will delete your personal data if you ask us to. The law says we must not contact you again if you ask us not to.  For this reason, we may need to keep the paper trail confirming deletion to make sure this happens

5.8 If you wish to contact us, please refer to Section 7 of this policy.

**6.0 SUPPLIERS**

6.1 We hold information about suppliers to enable us to contact you.

6.2 The personal information we hold is your name, job title, and maybe your work email address.

6.3 We will continue to hold your personal details for two years after your last invoice with us. After which we will either delete your personal data or keep it because you have asked us to.

6.4 This information is only disclosed to employees of Kelsey Media Ltd and contracted processors. For example, this may be an agency who sends mail for us.  It is possible we might need to disclose this information for legal purposes.

6.5 The legal basis for processing your data is ‘contract’ while we are your customer.  When you are no longer active supplier, it is ‘legitimate interest’ because we may want to order from you again.

6.6 Your rights concerning your personal data are:

  * You can ask to see the personal data we hold about you and we will show you, free of charge
  * We will update the personal data to correct errors when you tell us about them
  * We will supply you with an electronic copy of the personal data we hold about you if you ask us to
  * We will stop processing your personal data if you tell us to
  * We will delete your personal data if you ask us to. The law says we must not contact you again if you ask us not to.  For this reason, we may need to keep the paper trail confirming deletion to make sure this happens

6.7 If you wish to contact us, please refer to Section 7 of this policy.

**7.0 CONTACT DETAILS**

Head Office:  
Kelsey Media, Cudham Tithe Barn, Cudham, Kent, TN16 3AG  
Telephone: 01959 541444

The Data Protection Officer:  
Kelsey Media, Cudham Tithe Barn, Cudham, Kent, TN16 3AG

Telephone: 01959 541444  
Email: [DPO@kelsey.co.uk](mailto:DPO@kelsey.co.uk)

Latest update: 8th November 2018
